{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Dragoman","incorrectAnswers":["Smicker","Grommet","Ragamuffin"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'an interpreter or professional guide for travelers'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Steven Spielberg","incorrectAnswers":["Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese","Alfred Hitchcock"],"question":"Which director directed Jurassic Park?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Vesuvius","incorrectAnswers":["Etna","Filicudi","Montecristo"],"question":"Which volcano caused the destruction of Pompeii?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"Lose Yourself\" by Eminem","incorrectAnswers":["\"Jumpin', Jumpin'\" by Destiny's Child","\"What I Got\" by Sublime","\"Basket Case\" by Green Day"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"Look / If you had / One shot / Or one opportunity / To seize everything you ever wanted / In one moment / Would you capture it / Or just let it slip?\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Spain","incorrectAnswers":["Italy","USA","Japan"],"question":"In Which Country Were The 1992 Olympics Held?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Kate Bush","incorrectAnswers":["David Bowie","John Lennon","George Michael"],"question":"Which British recording artist released the song 'Wuthering Heights'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Mustard","incorrectAnswers":["Ketchup","Mayonnaise","Relish"],"question":"What is the name of the condiment made with the seeds of plants of the genus Brassica?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Red with five yellow stars in the top left.","incorrectAnswers":["Blue with a yellow cross extending to the edges.","Red with a black two headed eagle in the center.","Green, with large white script and a sword."],"question":"What does the flag of China look like?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Macauley Culkin","incorrectAnswers":["Bill Murray","Andy Serkis","Al Pacino"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Kevin McCallister in Home Alone?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Yoido Island","incorrectAnswers":["Jeju Island","Ulleungdo Island","Ganghwado Island"],"question":"Which island, home to the Korean Stock Exchange, is sometimes called' the Korean Manhattan'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Dune","incorrectAnswers":["Foundation","The Earthsea Cycle","Neuromancer"],"question":"Which science fiction novel features Duke Leto Atreides & the Harkonnens?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Que sera sera","incorrectAnswers":["Carpe diem","Cogito ergo sum","Hakuna Matata"],"question":"What popular maxim is the title of a 1956 song by Doris Day?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The origin and spread of diseases","incorrectAnswers":["Glass","The Sun","The preparation of books and manuscripts"],"question":"What is epidemiology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"God","incorrectAnswers":["Noah","Joseph","King Herod"],"question":"According to the Bible who is Jesus's father?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Arthur Conan Doyle","incorrectAnswers":["Agatha Christie","Oscar Wilde","George Orwell"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Man with the Twisted Lip'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Seven","incorrectAnswers":["Ten","White","One"],"question":"What does the word 'sept' mean in French?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"An old man travels in his house equipped with balloons, inadvertently taking a young stowaway.","incorrectAnswers":["A sole survivor tells of the twisty events leading up to a horrific gun battle on a boat.","In the future, a small waste-collecting robot inadvertently embarks on a space journey.","A man deeply immersed in the Edinburgh drug scene tries to clean up and get out."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Up?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Mali","incorrectAnswers":["Turkey","Scotland","Japan"],"question":"In which country would you find the city of Timbuktu?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"El Salvador","incorrectAnswers":["Nicaragua","Costa Rica","Panama"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Guatemala?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Polaris","incorrectAnswers":["Yamaha","Sirius","Canis Majoris"],"question":"As what is the North Star also known?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Michael Jordan","incorrectAnswers":["Kobe Bryant","LeBron James","Shaquille O'Neal"],"question":"Which basketball superstar took a time-out in his professional career to play minor league baseball?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Fyodor Dostoyevsky","incorrectAnswers":["Vladimir Nabokov","Leo Tolstoy","Mikhail Bulgakov"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Notes from Underground'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"32","incorrectAnswers":["2","50","24"],"question":"How many teeth does thr average adult human have?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Belmopan","incorrectAnswers":["Roseau","Dodoma","Baku"],"question":"What is the capital city of Belize?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Swiss","incorrectAnswers":["Gouda","Feta","Parmesan"],"question":"What type of cheese is used in a Reuben sandwich?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Michael Douglas","incorrectAnswers":["Ben Kingsley","Kiefer Sutherland","Shah Rukh Khan"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Hank Pym in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"The Bees","incorrectAnswers":["The Blues","The Hoops","The Red Devils"],"question":"What is the nickname of the English football team Brentford?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Bruce Springsteen","incorrectAnswers":["Eric Clapton","Neil Young","Alanis Morissette"],"question":"Which American musician released the album 'Born in the U.S.A.'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Tom Collins","incorrectAnswers":["Singapore Sling","Long Island Iced Tea","Martini"],"question":"Which Cocktail is made from gin, lemon, sugar and soda water?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Stromboli","incorrectAnswers":["The Evil Queen","Ursula","Maleficent"],"question":"What is the name of the villain in Pinocchio?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Sweden","incorrectAnswers":["Hungary","Kenya","Saudi Arabia"],"question":"Which of these countries has blue on its flag?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"On the Waterfront","incorrectAnswers":["National Lampoon's Animal House","The Third Man","Gangs of New York"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Terry Malloy'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Senegal","incorrectAnswers":["Bosnia and Herzegovina","Singapore","Sudan"],"question":"Which region of the world uses '.sn' at the end of its web addresses?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Victor","incorrectAnswers":["Vague","Valve","Vile"],"question":"What word is used in the NATO Phonetic Alphabet for the letter V?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Tariff","incorrectAnswers":["Sales Tax","Trade Tax","Bordereux"],"question":"What is the term for a tax on a good or service imported from another country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Pictographs","incorrectAnswers":["Alphabet","Demotics","Cuneiform"],"question":"What did the Aztecs use as a form of writing?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Richard Nixon","incorrectAnswers":["John F Kennedy","Gerald Ford","Lyndon B Johnson"],"question":"Who made the first phone call to the moon?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Bakewell Tart","incorrectAnswers":["Eton Mess","Sticky Toffee Pudding","Tiramisu"],"question":"Which dessert is named after a town in Derbyshire, England?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Oak","incorrectAnswers":["Pine","Cedar","Walnut"],"question":"Which tree do Druids regard sacred ?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Greece","incorrectAnswers":["Italy","Spain","France"],"question":"Which Mediterranean country includes places such as Stavros, Apsalos \nand Katsikas?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"British Officers","incorrectAnswers":["Indian Rebels","French Prisoners","Chinese Spies"],"question":"Who was forced into the Black Hole of Calcutta?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"New Orleans Pelicans","incorrectAnswers":["New Orleans Rockets","New Orleans Suns","New Orleans Blackhawks"],"question":"Which of these is a basketball team based in New Orleans?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beatles","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Feeder","Uriah Heep"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'Get Back'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Ralph Fiennes","incorrectAnswers":["Brian Cox","Mark Wahlberg","Leonardo DiCaprio"],"question":"Which actor has starred in both Harry Potter and Skyfall?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"James Madison","incorrectAnswers":["Zachary Taylor","John Adams","Herbert Hoover"],"question":"Who was the 4th president of the USA, in term during the period 1809–1817?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Flags","incorrectAnswers":["Spiders","Languages","God"],"question":"What is Vexillology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Arthur's Seat ","incorrectAnswers":["William Wallace","John o' Groats","Mount Murphy"],"question":"What is the name of the extinct volcano that rises above Edinburgh?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Macduff","incorrectAnswers":["Macburn","Lady Macbeth","Duncan"],"question":"Who killed Macbeth?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Lithuania","incorrectAnswers":["Norway","Papua New Guinea","Suriname"],"question":"Vilnius is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"West Germany","incorrectAnswers":["France","Italy","Argentina"],"question":"Which country won the 1990 FIFA World Cup, hosted in Italy?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Lyndon B. Johnson","incorrectAnswers":["John F. Kennedy","Richard Nixon","Jimmy Carter"],"question":"Which president signed the Civil Rights Act of 1964?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Blood Meridian","incorrectAnswers":["Pale Fire","Howards End","The Quiet American"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Judge Holden'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"It is used in liquid fertilizers, potassium soaps and detergents.","incorrectAnswers":["It is used as an ingredient in baking.","It is used as a building material.","It is used to relieve pain."],"question":"What is the chemical potassium hydroxide often used for?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Tailor","incorrectAnswers":["Gambler","Dancer","Maid"],"question":"According To The Lyrics Of The Song “House Of The Rising Sun” What Was The Occupation Of Their Mother?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Boar","incorrectAnswers":["A Drake","A Tom","A Ram"],"question":"What is a male guinea pig known as?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Poseidon","incorrectAnswers":["Hercules","Athena","Eros"],"question":"Neptune Was The Roman God Of The Oceans, What Name Did The Greeks Use?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Austria","incorrectAnswers":["Bulgaria","Sweden","Ireland"],"question":"Where would you find the city of Vienna?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The 1960s","incorrectAnswers":["The 1950s","The 1970s","The 1980s"],"question":"Which decade saw the Stonewall Riots in New York City, which helped to initiate the gay rights movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"A Pineapple","incorrectAnswers":["A Strawberry","An Apple","A Raspberry"],"question":"What Type Of Fruit Is Depicted On Top Of The Men's Singles Trophy At Wimbledon?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A code-breaking computer","incorrectAnswers":["A nuclear-resistant tank","A supersonic bomber","An intercontinental missile"],"question":"What Was The Colossus, Developed In Buckinghamshire In 1943?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Robert Downey Jr.","incorrectAnswers":["Chris Evans","Chris Hemsworth","Tom Holland"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Iron Man in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Green Bay","incorrectAnswers":["Buffalo","Jacksonville","San Diego"],"question":"What city is the smallest in the United States to have an NFL franchise?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Monochrome","incorrectAnswers":["Magenta","Unicolor","Solohue"],"question":"What word describes a painting executed in a single color?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Don't You Want Me Baby","incorrectAnswers":["Never Tear Us Apart","What is Love","Slave To The Rhythm"],"question":"What Song Features The Lyric \"I Was Working As A Waitress In A Cocktail Bar\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Mercedez-Benz","incorrectAnswers":["Ford","Jaguar","Audi"],"question":"Which motoring brand is associated with the marketing slogan 'Engineered to Move the Human Spirit'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The Future","incorrectAnswers":["Science Fiction","Palm Reading","Drugs"],"question":"What is futurology the study of?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Oliver Cromwell","incorrectAnswers":["James I","Henry VIII","Victoria"],"question":"Who banned Christmas Carol's in England between the years of 1649 and 1660?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Nicaragua","incorrectAnswers":["Niger","Nigeria","Namibia"],"question":"Which region of the world uses '.ni' at the end of its web addresses?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Geeks","incorrectAnswers":["Peaks","Shrieks","Sikhs"],"question":"What is the missing word in the TV title 'Freaks and ___'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Dendrite","incorrectAnswers":["Axon","Synapse","Glia"],"question":"What is the name for the extension on a neuron that receives signals from other neurons?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Zeta","incorrectAnswers":["Delta","Omega","Beta"],"question":"What is the 6th letter of the Greek alphabet?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"It's becoming more enjoyable as time goes on","incorrectAnswers":["It's getting too big","It's going bad quickly","It's losing its flavor"],"question":"What does it mean when someone says that \"it's growing on you\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Stomata","incorrectAnswers":["Stigma","Sepal","Petal"],"question":"What word describes the porous openings on the surface of leaves?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Al Pacino","incorrectAnswers":["Macauley Culkin","Robert Shaw","Arnold Schwarzenegger"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Tony Montana in Scarface?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Black","incorrectAnswers":["White","Red","Brown"],"question":"What Colour Is The 8 Ball In A Game Of Pool?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Matrix","incorrectAnswers":["The Lord of the Rings: The Fellowship of the Ring","Seven","The Big Lebowski"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A hacker discovers the life he knows is the elaborate deception of an evil cyber-intelligence.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Helen Mirren","incorrectAnswers":["Kathy Bates","Kirsten Dunst","Sandra Bæ Hovedr"],"question":"Which actress has played roles in films including The Queen and National Treasure: Book of Secrets?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Quire","incorrectAnswers":["Whiffler","Ragamuffin","Ragamuffin"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'two dozen sheets of paper'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Niger","incorrectAnswers":["New Zealand","Nepal","Netherlands"],"question":"Which region of the world uses '.ne' at the end of its web addresses?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"France","incorrectAnswers":["Germany","Spain","Brazil"],"question":"Which country won the 1998 FIFA World Cup, hosted in France?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Green Day","incorrectAnswers":["Mastodon","Fall Out Boy","Blink-182"],"question":"'Dookie' is a classic 90's punk rock album by which band?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Mary Jane Girls","incorrectAnswers":["OMC","Digable Planets","The Vapors"],"question":"'In My House' was a one hit wonder by which artist?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Robert Redford","incorrectAnswers":["Jeff Goldblum","Jeff Bridges","Anthony Mackie"],"question":"Who plays the role of Alexander Pierce in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone","incorrectAnswers":["The Battle of the Labyrinth","Harry Potter and the Half-Blood Prince","The Sea of Monsters"],"question":"Which piece of written work starts with the line 'Mr and Mrs Dursley, of number four, Privet Drive, were proud to say that they were perfectly normal, thank you very much.'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Doctor Who","incorrectAnswers":["Star Trek","The X-Files","The Twilight Zone"],"question":"Which popular science fiction TV show features a machine called The TARDIS?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Telekinesis","incorrectAnswers":["Telepathy","Invisibility","Pyrokinesis"],"question":"What is the ability possessed by Carrie in the novel by Stephen King?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Indira Gandhi","incorrectAnswers":["Sarojini Naidu","Ratan Tata","Gauri Khan"],"question":"Who was the first female prime minister of India?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Hardness","incorrectAnswers":["Thickness","Conductivity","Resistance"],"question":"What Is Moh's Scale A Measure Of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Barbie","incorrectAnswers":["My Little Pony","American Girl","Bratz"],"question":"Which iconic dress-up doll was released in the USA in 1959?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Mineraloid","incorrectAnswers":["Flotsam","Gemstone","Pseudomineral"],"question":"What is the name given to a naturally occurring mineral-like substance that does not demonstrate crystallinity?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Braveheart","incorrectAnswers":["Trainspotting","My Neighbour Totoro","Apocalypse Now"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A Scottish warrior leads his countrymen in a rebellion to free his homeland.'","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Watergate","incorrectAnswers":["Hotelgate","Croneygate","Corruptiongate"],"question":"What was the name of the scandal that forced President Nixon to resign?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Lari","incorrectAnswers":["Dinar","Dollar","Terpo"],"question":"What is the basic unit of currency for Georgia (country)?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"China","incorrectAnswers":["Angola","Sri Lanka","Malawi"],"question":"Cantonese is a language spoken in which of these countries?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Bulgaria","incorrectAnswers":["Brunei","Israel","Andorra"],"question":"Sofia is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Achy Breaky Heart","incorrectAnswers":["Rock Me Amedeus","Barbie Girl","Lovefool"],"question":"What song did Billy Ray Cyrus have a hit with in 1992?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Venezuela","incorrectAnswers":["Vietnam","Montenegro","Vanuatu"],"question":"Which region of the world uses '.ve' at the end of its web addresses?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Internet Service Provider","incorrectAnswers":["Internet Service Portal","Internet Software Provider","Internet Search Provider"],"question":"In computer networking, is the full form of tje initials ISP?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Prunes ","incorrectAnswers":["Figs","Dates","Sultanas"],"question":"What are dried plums called?","difficulty":"hard"},